MADELEINE GUETTLER

Professional Summary

A dedicated and determined individual with strong communication and teamwork skills. My goal in life is to tackle inequality gaps through social work and data science. Highly organized, hardworking, perfectionistic, and driven.

Accomplishments

- Admittance into Consortium for Computing Sciences in Colleges Conference
- Member of Sigma Xi, The Scientific Research Honor Society
- Assistant Concertmaster/Principle throughout seven years at Boston Youth Symphony Orchestras

Work History

Simmons University - Research Assistant

Boston, MA

Spring 2022 – Current

- Assist Computational linguistics professor at Simmons in her NSF funded prosody
- Team up with students across several universities to clean up and manipulate data. In addition to setting up experiments focusing on prosody-based hypotheses for participants to take part in.
- Currently exploring different machine learning algorithms such as random forest and k-means to find optimal attributes/parameters for incoming data.

Simmons University - Teacher Assistant

Boston, MA

Fall 2022 – January 2024

- Engaged in helping students understand statistic concepts in Intro to Stats in addition to learning how to code in R
- Meet bi-weekly with other teacher assistants and course professors to discuss areas that teacher assistants could help support students in based off of previous semesters.

Hope Gain Center of West Michigan - New Program Committee Member Grand Rapids, MI

March 2021 - April 2022

- Created support programs for individuals struggling with mental health.
- Give seminars, do research, and help in fundamental key steps necessary to create up and running programs.

MGH Center for Systems Biology Research Informatics Core – Web Intern Boston, MA

Spring 2019 – Spring 2021

- Helped design/create websites for organizations within Massachusetts General Brigham and outside clients meant to help with better data management.
- Developed key communication, teamwork, and time management skills through consistently working closely with clients and colleagues.

Conferences and Presentations

Machine Learning in Prosody and Meaning

Consortium for Computing Sciences in Colleges | Spring 2023

Topic: Identifying what are the best attributes and optimal number of clusters that help predict mirativity

Navigating the Iterative Process Machine Learning and Linguistic Research

Consortium for Computing Sciences in Colleges | Spring 2023

Topic: The usefulness of machine learning with prosody-meaning mappings where linguistic theory does not provide a clear framework.





617-888-5046



Newton, MA, 02459

Skills

- Microsoft PowerPoint,
- Microsoft Excel
- Python
- R Programming
- MongoDB, MySQL

Education

Expected in May 2024

Simmons University

Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science: Data

Science

Cumulative GPA: 4.0

Relevant Coursework:

STAT 227 – Intermediate

Statistics: Design & Analysis

STAT 228 – Introduction to

Data Science

STAT 338 – Probability

STAT 339 – Statistical Theory

MATH 211 – Linear Algebra

CS 221 – Database Management

CS 346 – Data Mining

CS 232 – Data Structures

SOCI 239 - Intro to Social

Research I

Expected in May 2024

Simmons University

Boston, MA

Minor in Social Work

Cumulative GPA: 4.0

Relevant Coursework:

SW 255 –Interviewing & Doc in

Human Service

SW 253 – Human Behavior in

Social Environment

BUS 234 – Organizational

Comm & Behavior

June 2018

Newton South High School

Newton, MA

High School Diploma

Languages

- English
- German